http://www.iglu.com/privacy

The
security of your personal information is of utmost importance to us. Below we
will set out the Privacy Policy of Iglu.com Limited. We operate under the names
of Iglu Cruise, Planet Cruise, Iglu Ski and Iglu Lapland. For any data that we
obtain from you, Iglu.com Limited is the data controller the purposes of
appropriate data protection laws.
Below
we outline what data we use, how is used and what choices and rights you have
in respect to the data that is held.
We are acting in compliance with current data protection laws in the UK and the
EU. Future changes to our Privacy Policy will be published on this page.
Enquiring
about a holiday
If
enquiring for information or a quote - you are able to contact us via the
telephone or by completing a form online. In doing so we will ask for some simple
contact details (phone number, email and name) as well as record details
of your general or specific requirements.
Our
team will then use this information to help find you a holiday and communicate
options to you. You may ask for our team to stop providing details of holidays
or offers tailored to your requirements at any point.
Booking
a holiday
In
proceeding to book a holiday, the information that we will require may vary
depending on a number of factors. These are:
- Whether we are acting as your travel agent or holiday operator.
- Who is providing individual travel services.
We must pass on the information required by those fulfilling your travel services.
We will only pass on information relevant to the service. We will work with any
suppliers to ensure that any data passed to them is adequately protected and
adheres to the levels of privacy and data security practised by us.
In
all cases we will record and securely store:
Along
with details of the holiday booked, any information that we may need to note
for the fulfilment of your holiday as well as details of any communication that
we may have with you or your travel service providers.
In
some instances we will also need:
-
Passenger
information, such as passport details, details of insurance policies held
and next of kin contacts.
-
Any
details that you require us to record to ensure that your needs are met. These
can include dietary requirements (which we understand, in some cases,
may give indication of your religion or ethnic origin) and medical needs (which
provide indication of matters of your health). It is essential that your
requirements in respect to these special categories of data are passed
to travel providers only where appropriate and essential to do so, therefore
ensuring the fulfilment of your holiday in accordance with your requirements.
Such details will only be collected on the basis of your consent but could be
essential for the smooth running of your holiday.
After
booking
Third
Party Review sites.
We
work with both TrustPilot and Feefo.
Once
a booking has been completed, we will provide your name, email address and
the name of the holiday booked to one of the above companies.
Your
information is used solely to send a survey on our behalf. This allows us to
measure the effectiveness of our services as well as provide you with an
opportunity to quickly and easily provide feedback which we can then act upon
as necessary. Your feedback is published on the appropriate third party site.
In each instance, we will be provided with details of who has left feedback,
though you will have the option to publish your feedback anonymously so that you
cannot be publically identified. We reserve the right to reply to reviews
publically, taking care not to communicate any personal information from which
you could be personally identified.
Should
you not prefer to be contacted by TrustPilot or Feefo or any other third party
site that operates similarly, let us know. In asking not to be contacted by
such parties will not prejudice the service provided to you in any way. Upon
booking, you will be provided with alternative methods of contacting our business
directly to provide feedback and get any immediate concerns or queries
addressed.
Communication
about your holiday
It
is important that we are able to contact you by email, telephone or letter
using the contact details obtained at the time of booking to keep you updated
about your holiday. This could be to:
-
Pass
on any important information from your tour operator or travel provider such as
enforced changes to your holiday.
Make
you aware of services to complement your specific upcoming holiday.
-
To
provide all appropriate documentation for your travel.
We
will only contact you with offers, promotions or details of available products
and services under the following circumstances.
-
You
have provided us with explicit consent to do so.
-
You
have an active enquiry with us (see 'Enquiring about a holiday').
-
You
have booked a holiday with us in recent times and we wish to share with you
offers for holidays that may similarly interest you.
We
will use securely held contact information and details of previous
activity including that collected digitally (see below) when you have visited
our websites.
We
may also collect details of how you use any marketing emails that we may send,
including whether you open our emails and what actions you take once you have.
Such information may be used to determine the marketing messages that you may
see.
We
assure you that you will always be able to ask us to stop marketing to you at
which point any and all direct marketing will cease (with the exception of any
campaigns that are currently in the pipeline for despatch - for example direct
mailings already submitted for fulfilment). All marketing emails issued by our
business will include an 'unsubscribe' link.
Iglu.com
Limited do not sell, trade or rent your personal details to third parties
unconnected to your holiday. Details are provided to suppliers connected to
your holiday for the purposes of the fulfilment of your holiday only.
Digitally
collected information
Information
collected digitally can include your IP address, data from your browser,
cookies (pieces of data stored on your computer) and how our website is used
and from what kind of device. This can be used for a number of purposes, such
as provide aggregate information as to how users may access our site to
providing a more individualised service, such as displaying our pages in the right language or personalisation of ads.
Cookies
This site uses cookies which are small text files that are placed on your machine to help the site provide a better user experience. In general, cookies are used to retain user preferences, store information, and provide anonymised tracking data to third party applications like Google Analytics. As a rule, cookies will make your browsing experience better. However, you may prefer to disable cookies on this site and on others.
How to control and delete cookies
The most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your browser. We suggest consulting the Help section of your browser or taking a look at the About Cookies website which offers guidance for all modern browsers
Types of Cookie Session cookies
Session cookies allow websites to link the actions of a user during a browser session. They may be used for a variety of purposes such as remembering what a user has put in their shopping basket as they browse around a site. These session cookies expire after a browser session so will not be stored longer term. For this reason session cookies may sometimes be considered less privacy intrusive than persistent cookies.
Persistent cookies
Persistent cookies are stored on a visitors computer in between browser sessions which allows the preferences or actions of the visitor across a website site to be remembered. Persistent cookies may be used for a variety of purposes including remembering visitors preferences and choices when using a website or to target advertising.
First and third party cookies
Whether a cookie is 'first' or 'third' party refers to the website or domain placing the cookie. First party cookies are cookies set the particular website that the user has chosen to visit. Third party cookies are cookies that are set by a domain other than the one being visited by the user.
Remarketing
This website uses Google AdWords, Criteo & Facebook remarketing services to advertise on third party websites to previous visitors to our site. This could be in the form of an advertisement on the Google search results page, a site in the Google Display Network, Criteo network, or Facebook. Third-party vendors, including Google & Facebook, use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits. Of course, any data collected will be used in accordance with our own privacy policy, as well as Google, Criteo & Facebook privacy policies.
You can opt-out of remarketing by visiting the links below:
For Google: https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en
For Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences/
For Criteo: https://www.criteo.com/privacy/
Your
rights to see, delete or amend data held about you
You
are entitled to access your personal data held by us at any time. Please email privacy@iglu.com to make such a request. We will be obliged
to offer any appropriate details within 30 days of the request. Please do
advise us if you are seeking a specific piece or pieces of data.
We
will only process your data for as long as it is deemed necessary after which
time it will be securely deleted. Any concerns about the ongoing processing of
data, including any corrections that may need to be made to any information
held, should also be directed to privacy@iglu.com.
Contact
Information: Iglu.com Ltd., 165 The Broadway, London, SW19 1NE
